<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>grasshopper on BIMGEEK</title>
    <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/categories/grasshopper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grasshopper on BIMGEEK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 18:30:09 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bimgeek.github.io/categories/grasshopper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Sheets from Excel</title>
      <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/create-sheets-from-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 18:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/create-sheets-from-excel/</guid>
      <description>This is a classic one! You&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across some version of this tutorial if you made any search about Dynamo. Let me show you how you can do it in Grasshopper🦗. In this video, I created a pretty basic script. This script reads sheet data (sheet number, sheet name, etc&amp;hellip;) from Excel then creates new sheets in Revit using this data. After the sheets have been created, the script updates specific sheet parameters using the Excel data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Fire Rating of Doors and Walls</title>
      <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/check-fire-rating-of-doors-and-walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/check-fire-rating-of-doors-and-walls/</guid>
      <description>🔥Checking Fire Rating of Doors and Walls🔥
In this tutorial I compared fire rating values of doors and their host walls. Then filtered doors that doesn’t have the same value as their host element. This was fairly simple example to demonstrate how to filter Revit data in Grasshopper.
#callout {background: #b3b3b33f;padding: 1.5em 1.25em;border-radius: 3px;display: flex;flex-direction: row;margin-bottom: 20px;}#callout-inner {margin-left: 1em;}@media (max-width: 767px) {#callout {padding: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Instance Parameter to Stacked Walls</title>
      <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/add-instance-parameter-to-stacked-walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 15:18:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/add-instance-parameter-to-stacked-walls/</guid>
      <description>💡Quick Revit Workaround💡
Did you know you can&amp;rsquo;t set Instance Parameters to Stacked Walls in Revit? I shared a workaround🔄 to add aninstance parameter as well as set a value of it in this video. Hope you like it 👍</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Objects to Topography</title>
      <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/project-objects-to-topography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 14:58:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/project-objects-to-topography/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone👋,
The topic of this tutorial is the projection of components into given topography. This is a task that can be easily automated with a simple script. Otherwise, manual placement of each object into a slanted surface would take a lot of time and kill your joy of life :). With this grasshopper script, we will get the location point of objects from Revit, project this point into Topography and use projected points as the new location point for tree families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Distribution on Topography</title>
      <link>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/random-distribution-on-topography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 16:06:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bimgeek.github.io/tutorials/random-distribution-on-topography/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone👋,
I created a tutorial on placing objects randomly on a topography using Grasshopper inside Revit and created a forest model as an example case. The tree🌳 family I&amp;rsquo;ve used is actually created by Gavin Crump. I gave him credit in the video as well😊. Please comment the topics you would like to see more content about. This tutorial is a great example to show how integrated Grasshopper and Revit are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
